Interests

ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE · COGNITIVE SCIENCE · NLP

My research broadly lies in the areas of human-centered computing. Specifically, I would like to advance the explainability of human behaviors by employing AI models, especially language processing.

Education

École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL)

Lausanne, Switzerland

PHD IN COMPUTER AND COMMUNICATION SCIENCES (EDIC)

Sep. 2022 -

- First project Advisor: Antoine Bosselut @ EPFL & Lonneke van der Plas @ IDIAP
- Second project Advisor: Frederic Kaplan & Maud Ehrmann & Boros Emanuela @ EPFL

Sungkyunkwan University (SKKU)

Seoul, South Korea

M.S. IN APPLIED ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

Aug. 2020 - Feb. 2022

- · Advisor: Eunil Park
- Master's Thesis: Understanding Difficulties of Content Filterings and Humans' Cognitive Bias in Algorithmic Recommendations

Sungkyunkwan University

Seoul, South Korea

B.A. IN PSYCHOLOGY

B.S. IN ENGINEERING, INTERDISCIPLINARY PROGRAM OF CONVERGENT SOFTWARE - SAMSUNG CONVERGENCE

Mar. 2016 - Aug. 2020

SOFTWARE COURSE

Research Experience

European Cooperation in Science &

Technology

Researcher
MULTIPLEYE

Sep. 2022 - Current

- Collaborating with the researchers in the project, main researcher as Nora Hollenstein, (Group leader) Jamal Nasir.
- Leading survey paper for using eye-tracking dataset to improve performance/explainability of NLP techniques.
- Revising the code for pre-processing eye-tracking dataset.

Research Assistant EPFL

DIGITAL HUMANITIES LAB

Apr. 2023 - Aug. 2023 (Expected)

- Advisor: Frederic Kaplan & Maud Ehrmann & Boros Emanuela
- · Fine-tuning adapter module with low-resource historical dataset to deploy knowledge from large language model (LLaMA).

Research Assistant EPFL

NLP LAB

Sep. 2022 - Feb. 2023

- Advisor: Antoine Bosselut & Lonneke van der Plas
- · Conducted prompt tuning to implement chain-of-thought prompt for measuring creativity ability of large language models.
- Constructed Linux environment for large language model (e.g., OPT175B, BLOOM175B) in EPFL cluster.
- Conducted data analysis for newly constructed persona dialogue dataset (Accepted in ACL'23).

Georgia Institute of Technology

(Remote

CLAWS LabJul. 2021 - Apr. 2022

· Advisor: Srijan Kumar

Research Intern

- Engaged in survey paper on analyzing the countering misinformation efforts of the crowds.
- Devised natural language processing method to debunk misinformation based on individual features of the crowds.

Undergraduate Research Assistant

SKKU

Jul. 2019 - Aug. 2020

DATA EXPERIENCE LAB

- Advisor: Eunil Park
- Explored user experience of augmented reality and virtual reality products (Funded by NRF of Korea)
- Developed a Deep Learning Model for Predicting Service Reuse (Funded by the NRF of Korea)

Publication

JUNE 16, 2023 SOYOUNG OH

- c4 Silin Gao, Beatriz Borges¹, Soyoung Oh¹, Deniz Bayzit¹, Saya Kanno, Hiromi Wakaki, Yuki Mitsufuji, & Antoine Bosselut (2023). PeaCoK: Persona Commonsense Knowledge for Consistent and Engaging Narratives. ACL 2023. [PDF]
- c3 Soyoung Oh, & Eunil Park (2022).

Are you aware of what you are watching? Role of machine heuristic in online content recommendations. ICWSM 2022 Workshop on Cyber Social Threats (CySoc 2022). [PDF]

c2 Sangeun Lee¹, Soyoung Oh¹, Minji Kim, & Eunil Park (2022).

Measuring Embedded Human-like Bias in Face Recognition Models. AAAI 2022 Workshop on Artificial Intelligence with Biased or Scarce Data (AIBSD 2022). [PDF]

c1 Soyoung Oh¹, Jisu Kim¹, Seungpeel Lee.¹, & Eunil Park (2021).

Jujeop: Korean Puns for K-pop Stars on Social Media. In Proceedings of the Ninth International Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Social Media 2021, NAACL HLT'21 Workshop. [PDF]

j7 Dahye Jeong¹, Soyoung Oh¹, & Eunil Park (2022).

DemoHash: Hashtag Recommendation based on User Demographic Information. Expert Systems With Applications. [HTML]

j6 Soyoung Oh, Honggeun Ji, Jina Kim, & Eunil Park (2022).

Deep learning model based on expectation confirmation theory to predict customer satisfaction in hospitality service. Information Technology & Tourism. [HTML]

- **j5** Honggeun Ji, **Soyoung Oh**, Jina Kim, & Eunil Park (2022). Integrating Deep Learning and Machine Translation for Understanding Unrefined Languages. CMC-Computers, Materials & Continua, 70(1), 669-678. [HTML]
- **j4** Jina Kim, Honggeun Ji, **Soyoung Oh**, Syjung Hwang, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2021). A deep hybrid learning model for customer repurchase behavior. Journal of Retailing and Consumer Services (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.219, Q2 in Business). [HTML]
- j3 Jina Kim, Yeonju Jang, Kunwoo Bae, Soyoung Oh, Namjeong Jeong, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2021). Between comments and repeat visit: capturing repeat visitors with a hybrid approach. Data Technologies and Applications. [HTML]
- j2 Soyoung Oh, Jina Kim, Honggeun Ji, Eunil Park, Jinyoung Han, Minsam Ko, & Moonyoung Lee (2020). Cross-cultural Comparison of Interactive Streaming Services: Evidence from Twitch. Telematics and Informatics, ISSN: 0736-5853 (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.139, Q1 in Information Science & Library Science). [HTML]
- j1 Jina Kim, Soyeon Shin, Kunwoo Bae, Soyoung Oh, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2020). Can AI be a content creator? Effects of content creators and information delivery methods on the psychology of content consumers. Telematics and Informatics, ISSN: 0736-5853 (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.139, Q1 in Information Science & Library Science). [HTML]

Teaching Experience _____

Teaching Assistant FPFI

CS486, INTERACTION DESIGN

Spring semester, 2023

Assisted making and grading assignments in the field of HCI.

Teaching Assistant SKKLI

AAl3020, Dept. of Applied Artificial Intelligence at Undergraduate Course

Fall semester, 2020

Led research project with undergraduate students and successfully submitted paper to conference [c2]

Instruction Assistant KINTEX, South Korea

IOT MAKER BOOTH @ E2FESTA2018

Sept. 2018

• Assisted making IoT lamp with Arduino

Work Experience

Silikal Korea Construction Chemicals Co., Ltd.

Seoul, South Korea

INTERN

INTERN

Silikal GmbH

May 2018 - Jul. 2018

· Done internship program with logistics, sales, and accounting.

Mainhausen, Germany

Feb. 2018 - Apr. 2018

• Done internship program at sales & sales support in Export, Import division.

Honors & Awards

JUNE 16, 2023 Soyoung Oh 2

2022	Attendance Scholarship, ICWSM-2022 Grant Program	ICWSM
2022	EDIC PhD Fellowship, A one-year fellowship	EPFL
2021	Attendance Scholarship, ICWSM-2021 Grant Program	ICWSM
2020	Bachelor's Degree Linked Master Program Scholarship, Full tuition of last semester of undergraduate	SKKU
2019	Travel Scholarship, Language Exchange student @ Okayama University	Campus Asia
2019	Academic Excellence Scholarship, 70% of tuition from Dept. of Social Science (GPA:4.4/4.5)	SKKU

Academic Services _____

2022	Student Volunteer, ICWSM'22 Virtual Conference	ICWSM
2022	Student Volunteer, FAccT'22 On-Site Conference	FAccT
2022	Reviewer, Reviewed papers @ alt.chi track	CHI
2021	Student Volunteer, NAACL HLT'21 Virtual Conference	NAACL

Skills

Programming Python, SPSS, LaTeX, JAVA, C
Machine Learning Tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch
HTML, CSS, Node.js

User Research Interviewing, Conducting surveys, Experimental Design

Languages Korean, English, Japanese

References _____

Eunil Park eunilpark@skku.edu, Assistant Professor @ Sungkyunkwan University **Antoine Bosselut** antoine.bosselut@epfl.ch, Tenure Track Assistant Professor @ EPFL **Lonneke van der Plas** lonneke.vanderplas@idiap.ch, Professor @ IDIAP